sagepay.co.uk 2009-11-23

# Sage Pay - Privacy policy

Privacy policy and cookie policy

#### 1\. About this policy

This is the privacy policy of Sage Pay, a division of Sage (UK) Limited ("Sage Pay"). It applies only to personal data as defined in s.1 of the 1998 Data Protection Act ("personal information" or "information") and not other types of business or general information. Broadly speaking, this is information that enables you to be identified, such as your name, address and email address. Please note that this policy will only relate to financial information about you if that financial information is personal data, as defined by that Act. The policy tells you who we are, how we collect personal information about you through this website, what we intend to use that information for, with whom we intend to share it, how we keep it secure, and how we transfer your information outside the European Economic Area ("EEA").

Please read this policy carefully. By accessing or using this website you are deemed to agree to the terms of this privacy policy, and if you do not agree with it, then you must not send us any personal information.

Note that if you follow a link from this site to another site, this policy will no longer apply. We are not responsible for other sites´ information handling practices. Use of your information by the owner of the linked site will normally be governed by that site´s privacy policy, which we encourage you to read.

Further information about privacy and data protection issues including the online Register of Data Controllers can be found on the [Information Commissioner´s](http://www.informationcommissioner.gov.uk/) website.

#### 2\. Who we are

We are Sage Pay, a division of Sage (UK) Limited, a company registered in England and Wales with company registration number 1045967. Our registered office is at North Park, Newcastle upon Tyne, NE13 9AA. Please see our Contact Us section for more information. If you have any queries about the information we hold on you, please contact our Data Protection Compliance Officer, who you may write to at the address above, or telephone on 0191 294 3000.

We are entered in the Register of Data Controllers with registration no. Z8245307.

#### 3\. How we collect information from you

3.1. By the use of "cookies" and other site usage tracking tools

"Cookies"

3.1.2. A cookie is a small text file which is transferred from a website and stored on your computer´s hard drive. It enables a website to "remember" who you are. Sage Pay never permanently stores any personal information in cookies (on any computer that you may use) that can be used to identify you, such as your name or account numbers. Please see section 3.1.4 about how we use temporary cookies.

3.1.3. Most browsers are automatically set to accept cookies but some browsers, such as Microsoft´s Internet Explorer or Netscape Navigator, allow you to configure your browser to restrict cookies or block all cookies if you wish. This will however affect your ability to log into and use our VSP Admin area, online application form and other restricted areas of our website. Browser-specific instructions on how to restrict or block cookies may be found on the Interactive Advertising Bureau´s website at [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

3.1.4. We use session cookies (which are temporary cookies) in the VSP Admin reporting system to remember customer information used to complete transactions through the VSP Terminal. Session cookies are deleted when you close your browser (i.e. the software program you use for searching and viewing various kinds of Internet resources such as information on a website, e.g. Microsoft´s Internet Explorer).

3.1.5. We do not use persistent cookies, i.e. cookies remain on your hard disk until you delete them.

3.1.6. No cookies on our site are controlled or used by third parties.

**Other tracking tools**

3.1.7. We do use a third party, Webtrends Inc., to help us collect anonymous information about how our website is used. For example, the software looks at which pages are most used, and the order in which they were visited. Webtrends uses SDC advanced tracking code and is a smart source data collector. Please see <https://ondemand.webtrends.com/privacypolicy.asp#PSFV> for further information about Webtrends.

Some of our web pages may contain other tools to help us understand how users use our website, to help us improve it. These tools do not store your information or any information which is specific to you.

**Further information**

3.1.8. More information on cookies and web beacons can be found at [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

3.2. By registration

3.2.1. We collect information about you that you provide to us when you register to use the services advertised on our site through our online application form.

3.2.2. We need you to give us certain information that will be indicated on the form that you are required to complete in order to register. It would help us if you give us any other information that you think will be relevant but you are under no obligation to do so.

3.3. Through traffic data and site statistics

3.3.1. We do keep a record of traffic data which is logged automatically by our server, such as your IP address, the URL you visited before ours, the URL you visit after leaving our site and which pages you visit.

3.3.2. We also collect some site statistics such as page hits and page views.

3.3.3. We are not readily able to identify any individual from traffic data or site statistics.

3.4. By you contacting us by other methods other than the website

3.4.1. The website provides various telephone and fax numbers and email addresses for you to contact us. We will collect information from you that you provide through any of these methods.

3.4.2. We may also collect other information that you supply to us after your initial contact with us.

#### 4\. Security and storage of information

4.1. We will keep your information secure by taking appropriate technical and organisational measures against its unauthorised or unlawful processing and against its accidental loss, destruction or damage.

4.2. Please remember that normal Internet email is insecure. We do however use secure connections in our direct debit sign up pages, online application form and VSP Admin area, so please use these pages when providing us with sensitive information.

4.3. We will store your information at least for the duration of any customer relationship we have with you, or as otherwise required by law (normally up to a maximum of 7 years for legal and tax reasons).

#### 5\. What your information is used for

5.1. If you register to receive services from us, we will use your information to fulfill your order and to provide you with the service you have requested.

5.2. If you register to use one of the community areas or other restricted areas on our website, such as the VSP Admin area, online application form or customer management system, we will use your information to provide the relevant service to you.

5.3. If you agree when you register with us, we will also use your information for marketing purposes. If you do not want the information we hold on you to be used in this manner, you should contact us either by writing to our Data Protection Compliance Officer at our registered office address given above, or by emailing us at [support@sagepay.com](mailto:support@sagepay.com), and telling us how we may use your information.

5.4. If you do not object, we will use the information we hold on you to contact you for feedback on your use of our services and/or our website.

5.5. We may use aggregated data about users of our site, sales patterns and other statistical data to improve our site, but it will not be possible to identify individuals from that aggregated data.

#### 6\. Sharing your information

6.1. We will not share your information with any other organisation except in the following circumstances.

6.1.1. We will share your information with third party businesses with whom we are jointly providing a service to you, so that this service can be provided. For example if you apply for Sage Merchant Services we will share relevant information about you to our merchant account service provider. That third party may also wish to use your information for other purposes and that third party should inform you of those purposes. We therefore encourage you to read any third party´s privacy policies.

6.1.2. We will share your information with other Sage group companies, for example Sage (UK) Limited, for them to use to inform you about their relevant products and services.

6.1.3. We will share your information with another organisation to which we transfer, or are in discussions to transfer, our rights and obligations under our agreement with you.

6.1.4. We may share your information with another organisation that buys our company or our assets, or with another organisation from which we acquire a company or business, and in the course of any preceding negotiations with that organisation, which may or may not lead to a sale.

6.1.5. We may share your information with our funders or potential funders, such as our bank and with our professional advisers who have a reasonable need to see it.

6.1.6. We may, on occasion, share your information with carefully selected businesses so that they can send you details of their products and services which are related to ours. Alternatively, we may on occasion use your information to send you details of the products and services of carefully selected businesses which are complementary to our own products and services. If you do not want the information we hold on you to be used in this manner, please email us at [support@sagepay.com](mailto:support@sagepay.com) or write to our Data Protection Compliance Officer at the registered office address given above.

6.1.7. We may provide anonymous aggregated data to reputable third parties on a commercial basis, but this will not include information specifically about you.

6.1.8. We will give third party providers who supply services to us, or who process information on our behalf, incidental access to your information but will always take steps to ensure their security measures are adequate to protect your information.

6.1.9. We will disclose your information to enforcement authorities if asked to do so, or to a third party in the context of actual or threatened legal proceedings or if otherwise required to do so by law.

#### 7\. Your rights

7.1. You have a right to rectify any errors in information we hold about you, and to change or correct any details you have already given us. Please inform us about changes to your details so that we can keep our records accurate and up-to-date. If you think we need to correct some information we hold on you, please email us at [support@sagepay.com](mailto:support@sagepay.com) or write to our Data Protection Compliance Officer at the registered office address given above.

7.2. You also have a right to be removed from any mailing list we hold at any time. To do this please email us at [support@sagepay.com](mailto:support@sagepay.com), or write to our Marketing Manager or Data Protection Compliance Officer at the registered office address given above.

7.3. You have a right to see a copy of the information we hold about you on payment of a statutory fee, which is currently £10. Before we agree to this, you must provide us with sufficient evidence of your identity and sufficient details of the information you wish to see to enable us to locate it.

#### 8\. Transfers outside Europe

8.1. We are obliged to satisfy ourselves before transferring your information to a country outside the EEA that it provides adequate protection for your data protection rights. The EEA comprises of the EU countries and Norway, Iceland and Liechtenstein. Countries outside the EEA may not give the same level of protection to your information as those within the EEA.

8.2. Our website is hosted in the UK and we do not transfer any information submitted by you through the site outside the EEA.
